翻译：Iz      Tiogy
校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
开心汉堡店第五季第十二集
蚂蚁之灾
除虫害公司
低一点
lower.
吉米・派丝多  竞选主席
再低
L-Lower.
再低一点
L-Little lower.
再低一点点
Just a tiny bit more.
对  放垃圾桶里
Yeah, in the trash.
现在用脚踩进去
Now, stomp it down with your foot.
露易丝  我开始觉得你可能
Louise, I'm beginning to think
并不在乎小吉米赢不赢得这次选举
you might not care about Jimmy Jr. winning this election.
蒂娜  你误会我了
You're so wrong, Tina.
我完全不在乎
I definitely don't care.
他会赢的
Well, he's going to win.
只有亨利・哈勃和他竞争
Henry Haber is the only other candidate,
而且他的竞选口号还是"我们能下棋"
and his campaign slogan is "Chess We Can."
我们能下棋
为亨利投一票
象棋是哪种游戏来着
Which game is chess again?
有方格的吗
The one with the checkers?
嗨  小吉米  齐克
Hi, Jimmy Jr., Zeke.
我的竞选海报怎么在垃圾桶里
Why is my campaign poster in the trash?
因为扔马桶里下不去
Because it won't fit in the toilet.
无所谓  数学俱乐部发起了投票
Doesn't matter-- the math club did a poll,
我的支持率上升了95点
and I'm up by 95 points.
压倒性优势[山体滑坡]啊  亲爱滴
We're talking landslide, baby.
泥石流来啦
Here come the mud!
-别闹我了  齐克  -抓住你了
- Okay, don't landslide me, Zeke. - I'm gonna get you.
抓住你了  来啊
I'm gonna get you. Come on, come on.
小吉米  你为什么会想当主席
Why do you even want to be president, Jimmy Jr.?
这样我就可以选舞曲了
To pick songs at dances.
每次都是快歌  慢歌
I hate it when it goes--
不快不慢的歌  我不喜欢
fast song, slow song, medium song.
我想要十首快歌  然后十首慢歌
I want ten fasts, then ten slows.
别说了  哈勃来了
Guys, shh, Haber Danger.
哈勃  你准备好认输了吗
Oh, hey, Habes-- you about ready to say uncle?
还有四天才到竞选日
The election is still four days away.
没听说过龟兔赛跑的故事吗
Ever hear of the tortoise and the hare?
没有
Uh, no.
你是在说小吉米的头发么
What're you sayin' about Jimmy Jr.'s hair?
"兔子"与"头发"同音
-他发质可好了  -我是说兔子
- It's nice! - I mean, "Hare," Like, rabbit.
你的头发像黄鼠狼的毛
Well, your hair looks like a weasel.
什么  我不是...
What? That's...
快歌  快歌  快歌
Fast song, fast song, fast song,
-快歌  快歌  -上  上
- fast song, fast song, fast song, - Go, go,
-快歌  -上  上
- fast song, fast... - go, go.
好耶  我支持小吉米当主席
All right, Jimmy Jr. for president.
这里有好多长柄勺
They got a lotta ladles.
我好喜欢这样说[英语为头韵]
Ooh, I liked saying that.
好多长柄勺  好多长柄勺
Lotta ladles, lotta ladles.
-好多长柄勺  -琳
- Lotta ladles, lotta ladles. - Lin.
-好多长柄勺  -琳  看这个
- Lotta ladles. - Lin, look at this.
-咋了  -一把刀要300美元
- What? - A kitchen knife for $300.
-300美元  -你说  如果我拿起来
$300?! You think if I pick it up,
是不是会有个大石头滚过来
a giant rock will come rolling at us?
电影《夺宝奇兵》主角
-啥  -我在说印第安纳・琼斯
Wha...? I'm talking about Indiana Jo...
谁是印第安纳・琼斯
Who the hell's Indiana Joe?
ふきなわ芙纪绳
鲍勃
Bob?
露易丝
Hi, Louise!
我擦  米莉
Crap! Millie!
你悄悄跟着我是想干嘛
What are you sneaking up on me for?
我给我俩设计了一个新的问候方式
I have a new secret handshake for us.
我把你的手指往后扳
I bend your finger really far back.
你把我的手指往后扳
And you bend my finger really far back.
然后一个熊抱
And then into a hug-shake!
别抱我
Stop hug-shaking me.
蒂娜  让她放手
Tina, get her off of me!
好吧  你能放下她吗
Okay, um, can you let her go?
最近怎么样  米莉
So what's new, Millie?
做一个四年级学生该做的
Oh, I'm just doing the fourth grade thing.
上课  抽时间休息
You know, taking some classes, squeezing in some recess.
每天忙来忙去
All that running around doesn't leave enough time
都没时间陪我最好的闺蜜了
for my best friend over here, though.
我们不是最好的朋友  米莉
We're not best friends, Millie.
我是你的天敌  我们爱着对方
Right, I'm your nemesis-- we love each other,
但又有些过节
but we've got some history.
你才不是我的天敌
You're not my nemesis.
我是  我们是彼此的天敌
We are, we're nemesises...es.
我们水火不容  却又深爱对方
We're rivals who are also totally obsessed
挚友天敌
with each other-- "Fremesises."
像蝙蝠侠和猫女
Oh, like Batman and Catwoman.
像袜子和凉鞋
And like socks and sandals.
米莉  这是你想象出来的
Millie, this is all in your head.
我们什么关系都没有  没有
We are nothing. Nothing!
一起去吃午饭吗
So we're on for lunch?
不  我们不一起
No, we're not on for anything.
我不想米莉出现在我周围
I want a Millie-free zone around me,
至少三张桌子以外
at least three lunch tables wide.
好吧  三英寸
Okay, three inches wide.
不是三英寸
Not three inches!
三张桌子
Three tables!
*小兔子露露*
*Little bunny Lou-Lou *
*蹦蹦跳跳穿过森林*
*Hopping through the forest... *
我都不知道为啥会进行这谈话
I don't even know why we're talking,
因为我不会买300美元的刀
because I am not getting a $300 knife.
当然啦
No, of course.
芙纪绳只有专业厨师才会用
The Fukinawa is really only for professional chefs...
其实  我就是专业厨师
Well, I'm a professional chef, actually.
这样啊
Of course.
-我真的是  -行  你是
- I am. - Absolutely you are.
但这也不代表我要买300美元的刀
It doesn't mean I buy $300 knives.
由"隐居山顶的工匠大师
That are "Hand-forged by a master blacksmith
手工锻造"
in his mountaintop workshop."
天  真的很好
Oh, boy, that's really good.
-这怎么就好了  -真的要买吗
- Why is that good? - Are we doing this?
我建议你们回去冷静24个小时考虑一下
Okay, I'm recommending a 24-hour cooling-off period.
我买了
I think we're doing this.
好吧  等等
Here, hold on.
拿回去炫耀吧
Spread it around.
"我们能下棋"[化用奥巴马竞选口号]
Chess we can.
谢谢
Thanks.
又是小吉米的支持者
Another Jimmy Jr. voter, huh?
我懂  大家都把他当朋友
I get it, he's everybody's friend.
我对政治不感兴趣
Yeah, I'm not really political.
我宁愿当大家的主席
I'd rather be everybody's president.
是朋友  但也是老大
You're their friend, but you're their boss.
有权力管他们  帮他们
You-you have power over 'em, to help them.
权力
Power...
-帮他们  -权力
- To help. - Power.
你的关注点全在权力上了
Y-You're focusing on the power.
权力
Power.
我  我先去...
I should... I'm gonna pass these out...
-权力  -发传单了
- Power. - Over here.
-不是吧  -我要竞选主席了  露易丝
- No. - I'm running for president, Louise.
米莉  主席竞选
我喜欢你海报的字体  米莉
I love your poster font, Millie.
恐怖片里常用的
They use it for horror movies.
福旺德老师
Mr. Frond?
四年级学生不能当主席  对吧
A fourth grader can't be president, right?
别有年级偏见嘛  露易丝
Don't be a grade-ist, Louise.
本来也是年轻人的事
It's a young person's job.
年轻人就是精力十足
There's a lot of burnout.
戴上
Button?
拿开
Get that thing away from me.
祝你能找到一个帮你投票的
And good luck convincing anybody to vote for you.
谢谢支持
Thanks for your support!
拜拜  米莉
Good-bye, Millie.
经过票数统计
With all the ballots counted,
瓦格斯塔夫小学新一任主席是米莉・弗洛克
Wagstaff's new president is Millie Frock.
不可能
I don't believe it!
露易丝  你能到台上来吗
Louise, can you come up here, please?
我想宣布一件事
I want to make an announcement.
谢谢  不必了
No, thank you.
摔跤队  把她带上来
Wrestling team, bring her to me.
放开我
Let me go!
家政队  把她缝在我身边
Home Ec class, sew her to my side.
五金组  打造一尊我们的雕像
Metal shop, make a metal sculpture of us.
合唱团  唱新校歌
Choir, sing my new school anthem.
*米莉和露易丝*
*Millie and Louise *
游行乐队
Marching band,
演奏《米莉露易丝序曲》
play the "Millie and Louise Overture."
舞蹈俱乐部  跳舞
Dance club, dance.
-啦啦队  吼起来  -不要
- Cheerleaders, cheer! - No, no, no.
米莉
Millie!
蒂娜  醒醒  醒醒
Tina, wake up, wake up.
真是太巧了
Oh, what a coincidence.
你也趁着我睡着时看我吗
You watch me when I sleep, too?
不是  我想加入支持小吉米的队伍
No, I want to join the Jimmy Jr. Campaign.
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard.
我明天教你用发泡彩胶
I'll show you how to use the puffy paints tomorrow.
我知道怎么用
No, I know how to use them.
我想负责他的竞选活动
I want to manage his campaign.
但那是我的工作
But, um, that's what I do.
嘘  继续睡觉吧
Shh, shush, just go back to sleep.
等你醒来时  你就是竞选经理助理了
When you wake up, you'll be assistant campaign manager.
-但我是  -嘘
- But I'm the... - Shh!
睡吧  睡吧
Sleepy, sleepy.
米莉已经有1%的支持率了
Millie is already up to one percent support.
我们开始领先这么多  现在只有这么多
Our lead was this, now it's this.
等等等等
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa,
什么叫"我们"领先
what do you mean "Our" Lead?
蒂娜挂了  然后让你当经理人了吗
Did Tina die and make you campaign manager?
我没挂  我只是睡着了
No, I didn't die, I just fell asleep.
我很受欢迎的
Well, I'm really popular.
我并不是很担心米莉
I'm not worried about Millie.
你应该担心
You should be.
上个月我们要给班里养的栗鼠取名
Last month we had to name the class chinchilla,
米莉想了个最烂的名字
and Millie had the worst idea of all.
"撒尿小公主"怎么样
How about Princess Little Piddles?
而我说出了大家的想法
I said what everyone was thinking.
"超恶毛绒公主"呢
How about Princess Fluffy Vomit?
对不对  米莉
Right, Millie?
你想取这个名字吧
Is that what you're going for?
你会毁掉它的鼠生的
You're gonna ruin this chinchilla's life.
然后我们都投了票
Then we all voted.
"撒尿小公主"
And somehow "Princess Little Piddles"
却意外当选
was the name the class picked!
米莉很有手段
Millie gets her way.
我都想她给我取名字了
I kind of want her to name me now.
至于竞选策略
On to campaign strategy--
我们得加码
we've got to up our game.
我可以再做一版海报
I can make another poster--
把"吉米"里的"I"画成勾
maybe I dot the "I" In "Jimmy" with a check mark?
有点狂野  不过也许有用
It's a little wild, but it just might work.
不错
That's a good...
-非常好的  -对
- That's actually a really good... - Yeah.
不 不要海报  印刷业已是过去式
No, no posters-- print is dead.
教室里有电视
We've got TVs in the classroom.
我们要广告
We need a commercial.
唯一能阻止米莉当选的东西
The only thing standing between us and a Millie-ocracy
就是小吉米的蠢萌脸
is Jimmy Jr.'s dumb pretty face.
这就是那把新刀  对吗
That's the new knife, huh?
对啊  有应必答
Yeah, it's so responsive.
跟我心有灵犀
It's, like, connected to my brain.
我心里想"切"  它就切了
I think "Chop," And it chops.
了解  我有个锤子也像这样
Yeah, I got a hammer like that.
男人和工具之间的联系
Us guys and our tools.
切  好的  鲍勃
Chop. Right away, Bob.
切  切  切
Chop, chop, chop, chop, chop, chop.
我觉得不用再切洋葱了  鲍勃
I think we got enough onions, Bob.
是该告诉你  还是你手上那败家玩意儿
Do I tell you or that car payment you're holding?
可以告诉我俩
You can tell us both.
我的锤子是麦克莱科林牌的
It's a McLecklin, my hammer.
你知道这个牌子吗  鲍勃
You know that brand, Bob? McLecklin?
我不了解锤子的品牌  泰迪
I don't know hammer brands, Teddy.
这是最好的牌子
They're the best--
锤子中的梅丽尔・斯特里普
they're like the Meryl Streep of hammers.
看这洋葱片
Ah, look at that slice.
我不是因为洋葱而哭
I'm not crying because of the onions,
是因为它的美丽
I'm crying because it's beautiful.
这么薄  都可以当纸巾用了
And it's so thin, I could actually use it as a tissue.
这个主意有点糟糕
that's a bad idea.
我拍了用锤子钉钉子的视频
I made a video of my hammer pounding nails.
用了娜坦莉梅[美国女歌手]的歌作背景音乐
I put a Natalie Merchant song under it.
献给我爸
Dedicated it to my dad.
但是你的锤子和我的刀相比
Yeah, but your hammer and my knife--
不是一个级别
it's not really the same thing.
要看看视频下的评论吗  鲍鲍
Want to read some of the comments, Bobby?
不用了
I don't... No.
这个人说  "太赞"
This guy-- he says, "Nailed it!"
网络啊
Oh, the Internet.
在上课之前  有一位
Before we begin, we have a message
学生会主席候选人要播放一段视频
from one of the candidates for student body president.
别急  不是亨利・哈勃
Settle down, it's not Henry Haber.
*我是小呀小吉米*
*I'm Jimmy Jr. Pesto *
*你知道我是第一*
*You know I am the best-o *
*别人跟我没法比*
*I'm cooler than the rest-o *
他写了《型男宣言》
He wrote the Hot-Guy Manifesto?
*我们都想当小吉米*
*We wish we were Jimmy Jr. Pesto *
变调
Key change!
*我是小呀小吉米*
*I'm Jimmy Jr. Pesto *
*背心是我的标记*
*You know me from the vest-o *
*有个目标要追寻*
*And I'm on a quest-o *
*要当学生会主席*
To be the president-o?
*你也希望自己是小吉米*
*You wish you were Jimmy Jr. Pesto. *
一起来吧
Let's do this!
太逊
Oh, barf.
真想给他一巴掌
I want to slap that kid.
对吧
I know, right? Oh...
瓦格斯塔夫新闻
这里是瓦格斯塔夫新闻  我是苔米
I'm Tammy with Wagstaff School News.
头条新闻  史上最烂广告是否将小吉米
Our top story-- did a super lame ad take Jimmy Jr.
从头号热门选手变成头号出局选手呢
from front runner to dumb bummer?
来看看民众的意见
We got reactions.
感觉自己被恶心的东西淹没了
I felt like I was covered in something gross,
亮瞎了我的眼
and I wanted to burn my eyeballs.
差不多就这样
Basically.
打死你我也不想给他编头发
I wouldn't braid his hair with your hands.
我*  抱歉
What a . Sorry.
我们搞砸了
We pooped the bed!
这个电视台有偏见
This station is biased.
大多数肯定还是喜欢的
I'm sure most people liked it.
最新消息
This just in--
米莉从小吉米处赢得30点支持率
Millie's gained 30 points on Jimmy Jr.
天呐
Oh, man.
好吧  一点小挫折
Okay, a little setback.
还能控制
Manageable.
现在我们知道什么不能做了
Now we know what not to do,
就在反方向上加把劲
so we go hard the other way.
坐稳了  各位  我们要开始抹黑了
Hang on, kids, we're going negative.
下午3点  瓦格斯塔夫小学
It's 3:00 p.m. at Wagstaff,
电话铃响起
and a telephone is ringing.
糕点售卖上的饼干卖完了
The bake sale is out of snickerdoodles.
也许听起来不重要
Maybe that doesn't sound like a big deal,
但有些人很喜欢这些饼干
but it is because some people really like them.
你希望谁来接听这通电话
Who do you want answering the call?
多处发育迟缓  行为古怪的
A fourth grader with multiple tardies
四年级学生
and multiple screws loose?
米莉  对糕点售卖太危险
Millie-- too dangerous for the bake sale,
对瓦格斯塔夫也太危险
too dangerous for Wagstaff.
那么  给小吉米投一票吧
Vote for Jimmy Jr. maybe.
太刻薄了
That was mean.
现在我知道我该投给谁了
Now I know who I'm voting for, for sure.
我们的哥哥很刻薄
Our big brother is mean?
那我们以后也会变刻薄吗
Is that what we're gonna turn into?
我不会允许的
I won't let you.
已经太迟了
I'm turning!
在我伤害你之前快走
Leave before I hurt you!
我勒个去
Oh, boy.
现在和我们在演播厅的是米莉
I'm here in the studio with Millie,
小吉米攻击性广告的受害者
the victim of a vicious Jimmy Jr. attack ad.
你还好吗
Girl, how you holding up?
我还好
I'm okay.
我很坚强
I'm strong.
我必须要坚强
I-I have to be strong.
为了瓦格斯塔夫
For Wagstaff.
恶意行为总会适得其反
You know what, negativity always backfires.
乔丝玲就总这样
Jocelyn does it all the time,
很逊  她本人也很逊
and it's lame, and she's lame.
-并非恶意  -这采访真好
- Not to be negative. - This is a great interview.
你很适合做这个
You know, you're really good at this.
我知道我很适合
I know, I know I am.
我都想支持你了  在电视上可以吗
I want to endorse you-- can I do that?
格兰特先生在摇头
Mr. Grant is shaking his head "No,"
但我还是要支持
but I'm doing it.
我拿到新选票结果了
And I'm getting a new poll.
你会赢的
Oh, my God, you're winning!
露易丝  这什么节奏
Louise, what's going on?
我本来该领先的
I'm supposed to be ahead.
尽在掌握之中
It's under control.
苔米告诉了我们答案
Tammy just handed us the answer.
恶意会适得其反
Negativity backfires.
当然也可以适得其"正"
Which means it also, uh, "Frontfires."
换策略
Change of strategy.
海报  开始
Posters, on it.
大家喜欢泡泡字体吗
Everybody like bubble letters?
不知道  挺浮夸的
I don't know, they're pretty flashy.
不  我们这次要疯狂抹黑小吉米
No, we go hard negative against Jimmy Jr.
什么
What?
跟上节奏啊  小帅哥
Try to keep up, pretty boy.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
这样米莉就会被责怪了
Millie gets blamed.
不会错的
See, it's foolproof.
我搞清楚这套规律了
I'm figuring this crap out, people.
这次信心满满
I'm feeling pretty confident now!
琳  我把一颗米切成了六块
Lin, I just cut a grain of rice into six pieces.
-快来看  -不
- Come look. - No!
-泰迪  看我和芙纪绳的成果  -没空
- Teddy, look at what my Fukinawa and I did. - Can't, Bob.
我把麦克莱科林带来了  正忙着修鸟巢
I brought my McLecklin in so I can finish off this birdhouse.
啥  你不能在这里搞这些
Wait, what? You can't do that here.
可我俩都是想做出些成就的工具爱好者啊
We're two guys with tools we love, making it happen.
泰迪  停下  不许拿那破锤子
Teddy, stop-- you don't compare a stupid hammer
和芙纪绳菜刀作比较
to a Fukinawa knife.
破锤子
Stupid hammer?
-还有你的破鸟巢  -完了  开始了
- And your birdhouse. - Oh, here we go.
我明白了
Oh, I understand.
你那小水果刀还不及
I understand that your weeny grapefruit knife
我锤子的一半
isn't half the tool my McLecklin is.
-一半都不到  -泰迪  收回那句话
- Not half! - Take that back, Teddy.
不  我们可以比试比试
I'm not going to. You know what, we'll settle it.
-比就比  -怎么比
- Okay, you're on. - How do we do that?
不知道  可能根本没法比
I don't know, it's probably impossible.
你们男人总爱攀比自己的小玩具
You men competing over your little toys.
让我感兴趣的唯一办法只有参与其中
The only way I'm gonna care about this is if I get involved.
我知道了  刀锤奥运会
Oh, I got it! Knife-Hammer Olympics.
我要策划个开幕式
I got to plan the opening ceremonies.
瓦格斯塔夫要问小吉米
Wagstaff has questions for Jimmy Jr.
为什么他总跳舞
Why does he dance all the time?
他在隐藏什么
What's he hiding?
他是想尿尿吗
Does he have to go?
为什么不别跳了直接去尿呢
Why doesn't he stop dancing and just go?
让小吉米快去厕所吧
Tell Jimmy Jr. To go to the bathroom already.
另外  这是他五年级时的照片
By the way, here's his fifth grade picture.
太丑了
It's terrible!
由渴望看到改变的瓦格斯塔夫学生提供
我支持率下降了70点
I'm down by 70 points?
没有人责怪米莉
No one blamed Millie.
为什么大家不按我们的想法走呢
Why won't people just think what we want them to think?!
你让小吉米从第一变成垫底
You turned Jimmy Jr. From hero to zero!
本来不该这样的
It's not supposed to go that way!
你让原本美好的东西毁于一旦
You took something beautiful, and tore it to pieces.
现在连我都不想和他玩儿了
I don't even want to hang out with him anymore!
别  齐克  别别
No, Zeke! No! No!
对不起  小吉
I'm sorry, Jay-Ju!
她把你毁了
She wrecked you!
天呐
Oh, God.
好  我们乘胜追击
Okay, we double down!
继续黑小吉米
We go after Jimmy Jr. harder.
怎么狠怎么来
Nothing's off limits--
口齿不清  怪咖兄弟  和蒂娜暧昧
the lisp, the weird brothers, dating Tina.
我不干了  露易丝
I quit, Louise.
行行  休息下
Right, right. Take a break. Okay.
休息结束  继续干活
Break's over. Back to work!
米莉说如果我退出
Millie said if I dropped out,
她可以让我选跳舞的曲目
she'd let me pick songs at dances.
我本来就是想要那个
It's all I wanted anyway.
我为你做了这么多
After all I've done!
再见  露易丝
Good-bye, Louise!
准备好佩戴我的徽章了吗  露易丝
Ready to wear my button, Louise?
永远别想
Never!
亨利  嗨
Henry, hi, uh, hey!
让我做你的竞选经理吧
Meet your new campaign manager.
第一步  先摘掉你的眼镜
First off, let's ditch those glasses.
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
我已经见识到你的能耐了
I've seen what your help can do.
但我们必须得阻止米莉
But we've got to stop Millie
当上主席  亨利
from becoming president, Henry!
那也许你该自己参加竞选
Then maybe you should run yourself.
你可以当自己的竞选经理
You can manage your own campaign.
你自己和自己强强联手  肯定无人能敌
The combination of you and you should be unstoppable.
我知道你在说反话  告诉你
Pretty sure you're being sarcastic, but you know what?
我还真就打算参加了
That's a great idea!
露易丝要竞选总统了  各位
Louise for president, everybody!
四耳主席  四耳主席
Two more ears! Two more ears!
这不好说  你真的觉得你能打败米莉吗
I don't know, Louise. Do you really think you can beat Millie?
我知道  我差得很远  但我有
Yes. I'm way behind, but I've got
来自亲朋草根阶层的重要支持
core grassroots support from friends and family.
你是给我戴了一枚米莉的徽章吗
And are you wearing a freaking Millie button?!
最近疯疯癫癫的可是你  不是米莉
Well, you've been the one acting crazy lately, not Millie!
我是被她逼的
Because she's making me act crazy!
她就是这么有心计
That's how good she is!
至少吉恩没有叛变
At least Gene is loyal.
这和米莉徽章发完了
And it has nothing to do
一点关系也没有
with Millie being out of buttons!
半毛钱没有
Nothing!
露易丝
Oh, Louise.
你真是被我迷住了
You're so obsessed with me.
我竞选主席  你也跟着竞选
I mean, I run for president, you run for president.
米莉  我知道你竞选总统的目的
Millie, I know you only want to be president
不过是想控制他人
so you can control people.
控制我
Control me!
投露易丝一票
她不是米莉
这次竞选关乎瓦格斯塔夫小学
This election is about Wagstaff.
咱别把个人恩怨牵扯进来好吗
Let's take the U and the I out of it.
看呐  "露易丝"变成"失败"了
Oh, look, now it spells "Lose."
原来露易丝的名字一直藏着这层意思
That was in Louise's name all along and we never saw it!
有意思  用"蒂娜"试试
This is fun. Do "Tina."
咱们竞选辩论场上见吧
Just wait for the debate, Millie.
我会把你打得一败涂地的
I'm gonna pin you to the mat.
-是吗  -是的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah!
对了  米莉
And speaking of pins, Millie,
还有多的徽章吗
get any more in or not yet?
比赛规则是这样的
Here is how it works.
菜刀和铁锤要分别完成一系列
The knife and the hammer will perform a series
级别相当的任务  来决定哪个更大
of parallel tasks designed to determine the biggest tool.
哪个更好
Better tool.
鲍勃  你切十个番茄
Bob, you will slice ten tomatoes
泰迪钉十根钉子  开始
while Teddy pounds ten nails into a board. Go!
-看我多快  -听听我这声音  鲍勃
- Going pretty fast over here, Teddy. - Listen to that tone, Bob!
-麦克莱科林威武  -芙纪绳无敌
- That's McLecklin, baby! - Fukinawa's in charge!
-别把大拇指切了  -别把小拇指砍了
- Don't hit your thumb! -Don't cut off your pinky!
-完成  -完成  -平手
- Done! - Done! - Tie!
第二局  换位赛
Round Two. Switch stations.
鲍勃  你撬开泰迪的钉子
Bob, pry up Teddy's nails.
泰迪  你把鲍勃的番茄钉回去  开始
Teddy, nail Bob's tomatoes back together and go!
钉番茄
Nail tomatoes?
好吧  我就想试试
All right, I took a shot.
你花一天就想了个这
It took you a day to think of this?
下一个是给露易丝的问题
The next question is to Louise.
你的哪些方面能让你成为一个合格的主席
What makes you best qualified to be president?
很简单
It's pretty simple.
我不是米莉
I'm not Millie.
各位  米莉根本不想当主席
People, Millie doesn't even want to be president.
她只是想引起我的注意
She just wants to be in my business.
她想像个连体婴一样
Live in my head and attach herself
和我黏在一起
like a conjoined twin.
变成我的第三只腿
Growing out of my side one leg,
第三只手臂  和第二个脑袋
one arm, and a head on my head.
答完了  谢谢
Good answer. Thank you.
好...吧
Uh, okay.
米莉  该你发言了
Millie, you have the floor.
大家已经知道我的未来规划了
You've heard my platform.
在此我还想补充一点
I would like to add that
我想增加学生咨询的预算
I would increase the budget for student counseling
好让露易丝能得到
so that Louise can get the help
她亟需的帮助
she clearly needs.
我亟需的帮助  什么...
The help that I need?! That's like...
我还支持延长课间休息时间
I'm also for longer recesses,
一对一互助计划  以及加量的甜品
a BESTIES system, and bigger desserts!
好耶
Yeah!
慢着  等等  一对一互助计划
Wait. Back up. "A BESTIES system"?
我是主持人  露易丝
I'm moderating, Louise!
一对一互助计划
"A BESTIES system"?
一对一  意味着每个人都有一个搭档
"BESTIES"-- it stands for "Buddying-up Everyone
帮助他提高校园生活质量
with Someone to Improve the Experience of School."
-不错嘛  -她还真擅长那一套
- That's elegant. - She's really good at that stuff.
上学不是件容易的事
School's hard.
大家都不应独自一人捱过
No one should have to go through it alone.
有了指定的搭档
With an assigned Bestie,
就有人陪你一起做作业
you'll have someone to do homework with,
陪你一起吃午餐
someone to sit with at lunch.
他还了解你所有的想法
Someone who knows all your thoughts,
甚至能补充完整你没说完的话
who can finish your sentences!
看吧  我赌米莉一定会
Here we go! What do you want to bet
会指定自己做我的搭档
Millie assigns herself as my Bestie, huh?
搭档的指定遵循姓氏的字母表顺序
Besties will be assigned alphabetically by first name.
喂  赞恩  我俩是搭档哦
Hey, Zane! You and me, bro!
这样一来谁和谁就成搭档了
Well, who does that put together?
露易丝和米莉  真是惊喜啊
Oh, Louise and Millie. What a surprise!
看到了没  各位
See, people?
米莉她疯了
Millie's obsessed!
这次是我
It's me now.
下次有可能就会是你
But tomorrow it might be you!
或者你  应该不会是你
Or you! Probably not you,
啃表男
boy sucking on watch.
露易丝  你太需要搭档了
Oh, Louise, you need a Bestie so bad!
谁给露易丝安排个搭档
Someone give Louise a Bestie!
她太可怜了
She's so sad.
那我们今天的辩论就到此结束
And that concludes our debate.
结果应该已经不言自明了
I think we know who won.
没问题问我吗  真的吗
No questions for me? Seriously?
哎呀  没看到你也在上面  亨利
Oh, didn't see you up there, Henry.
辩论后抱抱
After-debate hug-shake!
你会喜欢我这个搭档的
You'll like being my Bestie.
因为你没得选
You'll have no choice!
五轮过后  依然是平手
So, after five rounds, we're dead even.
还把钉子钉到柜台上了
And we accidentally nailed the board to the counter.
真糟糕  钉子怎么长这么长
That was bad. Who knew nails were so long?
对不起
Sorry.
但这让我想到了下一个比赛项目
But it gives me an idea for the next event.
谁最先在柜台上凿出洞谁就赢  开始
Who can make a hole in the counter first? Go!
我们肯定会后悔这么干的
Oh, we're really gonna regret this!
我帮你修好  用我的铁锤
I'll fix it later... with my hammer!
你才不会  用你那玩意儿啥都修不好
No, you won't! You'll never fix anything with that!
-我会  -我还是过会儿再来吧
- Yes, I will! - I'll come back later.
拜  莫特
Bye, Mort!
喂  小孩  喂
Hey, kid! Yeah, kid!
来  给我投一票
You, yeah! Hey, come on, vote for me!
拜托  拉我这候选人一把
Come on, help a candidate out.
真恶心  她还没放弃呢
Oh, gross, she's still running.
尽量避免眼神接触  往前走
Don't make eye contact, just keep walking.
我看到你了  乔丝玲
I saw you, Jocelyn!
往前走  往前走
Keep walking, keep walking.
我也是个人啊  看看我
I'm a human being! Look at me!
我会给你投票的  露易丝
I'll vote for you, Louise.
谢谢你  安迪
Thanks, Andy.
人家是奥利  别想我给你投了
I'm Ollie! Forget it!
那我是谁
Which one am I?
我要输了
I'm gonna lose.
"线索是辫子
"Follow the braid,
翻翻档案
"Check the files,
会有惊喜出现"
"What you find will make you smile."
也许跟扎辫子的人有关
Maybe someone who wears braids.
美国饶舌歌手
史诺普・道格吗  查查史诺普・道格
Snoop Dogg? Follow Snoop Dogg.
我已经查过了
I already do.
贴的基本都是转发和食谱
Mostly retweets and recipes.
辫子  艾比
Braids! Abby!
可她和这一切有什么关系
But how does she figure into this?
注意  所有学生现在去体育馆
Attention-- all students to the gymnasium.
给米莉...给主席的投票
Voting for Mill... president
将在15分钟后开始
will begin in 15 minutes.
我们得溜进福旺德老师的办公室
We've got to sneak into Frond's office,
看看他那儿有什么关于艾比的情报
and see what he's got on Abby.
好吧  祝好运
Okay, good luck.
我去给米莉投票了  拜
I have to go vote for Millie, bye.
不  蒂娜
No, Tina!
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我需要更多人手
I need an extra pair of hands.
你已经搞砸过一个竞选了
You messed up the campaign.
你又不愿意听我的
You wouldn't listen to me.
是的  但你得对家族忠诚啊
Yes, but party loyalty?
我们都是贝尔彻家的一员
We're both registered Belchers.
我确实是贝尔彻家的
I am a Belcher.
对啊  我们是放屁家族
Yay, us! The farty party!
快  翻翻档案
Quick, we'll dig through his files
看能找到什么线索
until we find something!
再翻翻禅意花园
And we'll dig through his Zen garden
看能不能开悟
until we find enlightenment.
翻出个蛤蜊也不错
Or a clam.
你看这档案多厚
Look at the size of this file.
那是艾比的吗
That's Abby's?
不  是你的
No, it's yours.
这是艾比的
Here's Abby's.
天呐
Oh, my God!
这里有关键线索
This changes everything!
我们得在投票开始前赶下去
We've got to get down there before the vote.
你们在我办公室做什么
What are you doing in my office?
你来你办公室做什么
What are you doing in your office?
我来拿橡皮指套
I came up to get a little rubber thing
一会儿数票用
for my finger to count votes with so...
我干嘛要跟你解释
I don't have to explain myself!
这是我办公室
It's my office!
我们正准备走的
Oh, we were just leaving.
好好呆着吧  哪儿都别想去
Get comfortable. You're not going anywhere.
谁  谁动了我的禅意花园
Who-who touched my Zen garden?!
要重新恢复禅意得花掉我一下午的时间
It's gonna take me all afternoon to re-Zen that thing.
拜托放了我们吧  福旺德老师
Please let us go, Mr. Frond!
不行  老实说  露易丝
No. Frankly, Louise,
你最近的行为太古怪了
your behavior lately has been extra erratic.
我需要对你进行辅导
You need some counseling.
天  福旺德老师  你说得对
Gosh, Mr. Frond, you're right.
我觉得我马上就能有新突破了
I think I might be on the verge of a breakthrough.
-很好  -快突破
- Oh, good. - Breakthrough!
烦死了  又让我跑步
Damn you for making me run!
我们得赶紧收尾了   琳
We got to wrap this up, Lin.
这对我们的生意可没好处
I mean, it's not great for business.
我们几乎把柜台给毁了
We totally screwed up the counter.
而且还没比出个结果
And nothing's settled.
反而引发了更多的问题
If anything, we've raised more questions.
我们依然是平局
I'm gonna say we're still even.
只剩最后一招了
And there's only one thing left.
菜刀对铁锤
Knife against hammer!
铁锤对菜刀
Hammer against knife!
铁对铁
Metal against metal!
不行  我们不来了
No way. We're-we're done.
平局也蛮好
A tie is good.
是的  鲍勃那么爱他那把刀
Yeah, Bob loves his knife.
我可不想毁了它
I'd hate to destroy it.
我的刀就是用铁锤做的  泰迪
My knife was made with hammers, Teddy.
用铁锤敲只会让它更结实
Hammering would actually make it stronger, so...
你尽管自我安慰吧
Whatever you want to tell yourself.
我先来
I get to go first!
五秒一局  开始
Five second rounds. Go!
芙纪绳  上
Fukinawa, go!
砍  砍  砍
Chop! Ch! Chop! Chop! Chop!
时间到  该铁锤了
Ding! Hammer time!
麦克莱科林
McLeckli
锤  锤  锤
Die! Die! Die! Die! Die!
它没变结实
It's not getting stronger!
芙纪绳
Fukinawa!
泰迪  可以停了  它已经死了
Teddy, you can stop! It's dead.
胜者诞生了
We got a winner!
给我看看
Let me see that thing.
老天  我也想要把麦克莱科林
God, I really want a McLecklin.
很好  还来得及
Good, we're not too late.
各位  在你们投票前
Everyone, before you vote,
我要话要对米莉说
I have something to say to Millie!
我想让大家也听听
And I want you all to hear it!
-放弃吧  露易丝  -我已经放弃了
- Just give up, Louise! - I have.
我只想
I just want to say to Millie
提前祝贺米莉  还有
early congratulations, and you know what?
我觉得有搭档应该蛮有意思的
I think being a Bestie will be fun.
你  你把露易丝怎么了
Wha-What have you done with Louise?
顺便说一句  我不会和你搭档
Oh, by the way, I won't be your Bestie.
-我会和艾比搭档  -什么
- I'll be Abby's. - Sorry?
你不知道吗
Oh, you didn't know?
艾比的真名是梅布尔
Abby's real name is Mabel.
"梅布尔"在"露易丝"和"米莉"之间
"Mabel" Comes between "Louise" And "Millie."
按字母表顺序
Your alphabetical rule.
等下  艾比叫梅布尔吗
Wait a minute-- Abby is Mabel?
艾比其实是梅布尔的昵称
Abby's actually a nickname for Mabel,
但没人知道  所以...
but no one knows that, so I guess...
我没跟你说话  艾比
I'm not talking to you, Abby!
-好吧  -梅布尔  你还爱编辫子吗
- Oh, okay. - Mabel, you still into braiding?
要不要用我头发试试
Want to take a whack at this mop?
你是喜欢法式辫还是鱼尾辫
Do you like French braids or a fishtail?
你是我搭档  你决定
Hey, you're my Bestie, you decide!
随便吧
Yeah, well, whatever,
到最后可能还是我俩搭档
we still might end up being Besties.
不可能  我是艾比的搭档
Except we won't. I'll be Abby's.
梅布尔的  随便吧
I mean Mabel's. Whatever.
-随便  -我们过会儿再聊吧  先投票
- Whatever. - But hey, we can talk later. Let's vote.
对  要投票  不过我们可以先聊聊
Yeah, let's vote. But let's talk now for a minute.
因为我们会是搭档  露易丝
Because we will be Besties, Louise!
不会的  这是你自己定的规则
Yeah. But no. Look, it's your rule.
等我当上主席
Well, when I'm president,
我可以改掉那烂规则  知道吗
I'll change the stupid rule, okay?
新规则会让我俩成为搭档
The new rule will make us Besties!
如果不行  我就再改
And if it doesn't, I'll change it again!
我再改
And I'll change it again!
因为你一定要和我搭档
Because you will be my Bestie!
如果需要除掉艾比或梅布尔
And if I have to get rid of Abby or Mabel
或任何人  我也会的
or whoever, I will!
小心点  那可是五股的辫子
Careful, that's a five-strand braid.
我花了一上午才辫好的
Took me all morning!
米莉
Millie!
表演结束
And... scene!
如果我当选  我会成立一个即兴表演俱乐部
If elected, I'll-I'll start an improv club.
我们再演一段
Let's do one more. Okay.
谁想个...职位出来
Someone throw out a-an, uh, occupation...
或者动物也行
And an animal?
有人说消防员吗
I heard fireman?
猪吗
And pig?
是有人说了猪吗
Did somebody say pig?
米莉好像输了
I think Millie just lost.
不可能  即兴表演中
Impossible-- the only losers
唯一的输家是观众
in improv are the audience.
等等  她这样我们还要喜欢她吗
Wait, do we still like her?
不喜欢了对吧  她好恶心  有没有
We don't, right? She's gross, right?
米莉因攻击艾比被取消竞选资格
Millie is disqualified for attacking Abby.
露易丝  你是民意投票的第二名
Louise, you were second in the poll.
你要当主席了
You're going to be president!
哇  头好晕
Whew, head rush!
我都已经开始有点醉心于权力了
I'm already a little drunk with power!
露易丝因擅闯我办公室被取消竞选资格
Louise is disqualified for breaking into my office.
这样一来  我们就没有候选人了
Oh. So we're out of candidates.
今年不会有主席了
No president this year.
对哦  还有亨利・哈勃
Oh, wait, Henry Haber.
恭喜你  亨利・哈勃
Congratulations, Henry Haber.
今天我的投票终于作数了
Hi. Uh, today my vote really counted.
在我的国家政变前  我也是主席来着
In my country, before the coup, I was president.
你走狗屎运了  亨利・哈勃
You are so freaking lucky, Henry Haber!
狗屎运
Luck.
你这样想的吗
Is that what you want to call it?
那是
Uh, yeah.
看来一切只是因为我走了狗屎运
I guess I was just lucky when I figured out
包括我想出要除掉小吉米
that to get rid of Jimmy Jr.,
就得把米莉拉进来
I had to lure Millie into the race.
包括我预见到
And I guess I was just lucky when I knew
她的参与会让你加入小吉米阵营
that she would pull you in on the Jimmy Jr. Side,
以及你会搞砸他的竞选
and that you would tank his campaign.
你怎么知道的
How could you know that?
一只名叫撒尿小公主的南美栗鼠告诉我的
A chinchilla named Princess Little Piddles told me.
啥
What?
我弟弟贺加斯目睹了全过程
My younger brother Hogarth saw the whole thing.
那名字本来没机会当选的
That name didn't have a chance
直到你因为那是米莉想出来的
till you went overboard dumping on it
就站起来对它大批特批
because it was Millie's idea.
让同学们都可怜起她来
And all the kids felt bad for her.
米莉让你完全失去理智了
Millie makes you completely irrational.
我没失去理智
I'm not irrational.
她只是让我抓狂
She just drives me totally insane!
为了打败米莉
Then I had to take care of Millie.
我让你也参加了竞选
So I got you to run.
然后我帮助你打败了她
Then I helped you take her down in a way
同时也让你自己出局了
that also took you down.
原来我们只是工具么
We were pawns?
你是想说"虾皮"吧
I believe you mean "Prawns."
你不可能那么聪明
You can't be that smart.
是的  我可以
Chess I can.
文武双全啊
Brains and brawn...
如果你有武的话我就会这么说
is what I would say if you had the brawn part.
你怎么能那样玩弄他人
How can you play with people's lives like that?
你以为自己是谁啊  亨利・哈勃
Who the hell do you think you are, Henry Haber?
你会成为优秀的主席的
You're gonna be an amazing president.
我曾经也是个优秀的主席
I was an amazing president.
后来呢
What happened?
政变
Coup.
*医生*
*Doctors have come*
*从遥远的城市*
*From distant cities *
*赶来看我*
*Just to see me *
*站在我床前*
*Stand over my bed *
*他们相信*
*Is believing *
*他们所见*
*What they're seeing *
*他们说我一定是个奇迹*
*They say I must be one of the wonders *
*上帝创造的奇迹*
*Of God's own creation *
*在我看来  他们根本*
*And as far as they can see they can offer *
*给不出合理的解释*
*No explanation.*